MOHIT KUMAR

+918076633870

mk9729708377@gmail.com o www.linkedin.com/in/mohit-kumar-3ba516149

Frontend developer with 3+ years of experience in the IT industry on web and mobile app using React JS and React Native. I am strong advocate for clean code practices, modules design pattern and continuous learning. I am always looking for new and innovative ways to bring my clients visions to life.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Project of the Month Award for MyHelpa and Received **Extra mile award** for employee of the month at Oodles Technologies.

SKILLS

Languages HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Prime React, Javascript, Typescript

Frameworks React JS, Redux, Context API, Next Js, React Native

Other tools and technologies: Github Actions, Google Analytics, Jenkins, Vivify Scrum, RestAPI, Socket.io

EXPERIENCE

Oodles Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Lead Frontend Development

Oct 2022 - March 2024 Gurgaon, Haryana

- Developed **MyHelpa** project using reactjs for web and react- native for android and IOS app .MyHelpa designed to support home care professionals with delivering outstanding care at home and Deployement of mobile app on **Google play store and App store**.
- As lead engineer handled project end-to-end translating **client requirements** into effective **sprints** and **managing a team of 5 members** while **also leading architectural decisions and development efforts**.
- Ensured 100% uptime for Increased productivity by several folds in frontend teams by setting up boilerplates and building reusable components.
- Elevated frontend code quality and consistency by integrating TypeScript and SonarQube; **reduced bugs by** 40% and improved team productivity by 35%

Sr. Associate Consultant- Frontend Development

Jan 2022 - Sept 2022

- Developed **Unikaksha** project using react. Unikaksha is an web page designed for online classes and different courses for Teachers and students.
- Achieved 30% growth by building out key features like 2 way sync bw tools like Jira, Real-time editor, showcasing strong leadership and strategic planning abilities.

Associate Consultant - Frontend Developer

Sept 2020 - Dec 2021

• Successfully built and delivered **3+ products with high-quality code** and user-friendly interfaces using React, Typescript.

Other Project

- Developed and enhanced my **Portfolio** website using **Next.js** and **Tailwind CSS** and use animations, frame motions for interactive design https://github.com/mohitkumar90/Portfolio.git
- Developed HealthNest mobile app assessment using **React Native** and **Redux** Drive Link and Github Link
- Designed Perpetual Strats web page using React JS for digital marketing Github Link

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology, JMIETI Radaur, Kurukshetra, Haryana

July 2016 - July 2020

Computer Science

OTHER SKILLS Communication, Problem-solving, Time management, Leadership, Teamwork.